Ames Family Papers, 1812-2012
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES II. REAL ESTATE
  - Winthrop Ames Mansion (North Easton, Massachusetts): correspondence and essay, 1950-70 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous U.S real estate: deeds, easements, leases, and insurance policies, 1896-1939 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Villa Balbianello (Lake Como, Italy)
    [See also SERIES IV: PHOTOGRAPHS and OVERSIZE MATERIALS]
    - History
      - "The Villa Balbianello," by General Butler Ames
        - Typescript and photocopies, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
        - Privately printed pamphlet, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Notes and correspondence, 1958-93, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Library holdings: correspondence, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - List of phonograph records, 1959,1967 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Clippings and articles, 1972, 1989-2009, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - "The Byron Garbage Divertor" [sic]: pen and ink drawing, Jun 1965 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Use by family and others
      - Correspondence and memoranda, 1955-75, undated (Box 5, Folder 11-20)
      - Rules of use, 1973-74, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - General management
      - Reports, 1955-60 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence with staff, 1958-75 (Box 6, Folder 2-17)
      - Monthly statements, 1961-75 (Box 6, Folder 18-31)
    - Legal
      - Estate of Butler Ames
        [see also SERIES III: INDIVIDUALS - Generation IV - Ames, Butler]
        - Appraisal of Villa Balbianello, 1955-56 (Box 7, Folder 1)
        - Overpayment of inheritance taxes: correspondence, 1956-70 (Box 7, Folder 2-4)
      - Estate of Oliver Ames: transfer of his share in the villa to his children: correspondence, 1972-73 (Box 7, Folder 5)
        [see also SERIES III. INDIVIDUALS - Generation V - Ames, Oliver]
      - National monument status: correspondence, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Sale
      - Correspondence
        - Jun 1974-Dec 1975 (Box 7, Folder 7-25)
        - 1976-77, undated (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
      - Appraisal, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Plat maps, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Artwork: correspondence, notes and photographs, 1974, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Other household contents: correspondence, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Capital gains tax dispute: correspondence and memoranda, Jan 1976-Aug 1980 (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
    - Development (proposed) and sale of Upland Meadow: correspondence, 1977-84 (Box 8, Folder 9-13)
  - Unidentified house: drawing, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
- SERIES III. INDIVIDUALS
  - GENERATION I: Butler, John (1782-1819): commissions, 1812 (photostats) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - GENERATION II
    - Ames, Oakes (1804-1873)
      [see also GENERATION VI: Davis, John. P., Jr.]
      - Oakes Ames: A Memoir, Riverside Press, 1883 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - General, 1962, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence: Puffer, Loring W., 1870, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Ames, Oliver: clipping and American National Biography entry, 1963, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Butler, Benjamin F.(1818-1893)
      - Biographical materials (Box 5)
        - Articles, clippings, poems, and certificates, 1861-2006, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
          [see also SERIES III. INDIVIDUALS - Ames, Blanche Ames - Art]
        - Commission, 1861 (photostat) (Box 5, Folder 7)
        - General Butler in New Orleans by James Parton: book and notes, 1964, undated (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
        - New Orleans Under General Butler by Howard P. Johnson, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 10)
        - Benjamin Franklin Butler: The Damnedest Yankee by Dick Nolan: correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 11)
        - Marriage to Sarah Hildreth: contract, account of wedding, and property transfer document, 1844, 1872 (Box 5, Folder 12)
        - Property valuations, 1861-69, undated (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
        - Estate: financial information and reports, 1900-37 (Box 5, Folder 15)
        - Biographies and memorials: correspondence, 1914-62 (Box 5, Folder 16-17)
        - Memorabilia: copper nameplates, wallets, and date book,1892, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence
        - Outgoing
          - Ames, Adelbert, 1870-89 (Box 10, Folder 1)
          - Ames, Blanche Butler, 1871-91 (Box 10, Folder 2)
          - Butler, Sarah Hildreth, 1871 (Box 10, Folder 3)
          - Others, 1860-89 (Box 10, Folder 4)
        - Incoming: Phillips, Wendell, 1867-75, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Books
        - Butler's Book, 1892 (unfoldered) (Box 10)
        - The Private and Official Correspondence of Benjamin F. Butler, 1917 (Box 10)
          - List of libraries that own this book and a copy of the top of the box in which the books were originally issued, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
          - Published copies of book (2 sets of 5 volumes each) (Box 11)
      - Professional activities: legal and financial
        - Correspondence
          - Outgoing, 1864-85 (Box 12, Folder 1)
          - Incoming, 1868-98 (Box 12, Folder 2-9)
        - Lawsuits
          - Bryant vs. Craig: speeches, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 1)
          - Butler vs. Huerfano Valley Ditch and Reservoir Co.: court document, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
          - Darling vs. Butler, 1885-94
            - Correspondence, 1885-94 (Box 13, Folder 3)
            - Legal documents, 1890-92 (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
          - Thomas Leitensdorfer vs. William M. Campbell and William Craig (pertaining to the Vigil and St. Vrain, and the Las Animas land grants)
            - Conveyances and deeds, 1886 (Box 13, Folder 6)
            - Legal documents, and notes, 1844-87, n.d (Box 13, Folder 7-9)
            - Legal pamphlets, 1875, 1885 (Box 13, Folder 10)
          - Machen vs. Butler: correspondence and legal documents, 1887-93 (Box 13, Folder 11)
          - Miscellaneous speeches and legal arguments, 1853-80, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
          - Miscellaneous court cases: legal documents, 1875 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Butler, Sarah Hildreth (1816-1876)
      - Biographical materials: clipping, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence
        - Outgoing: Blanche Butler Ames (daughter), 1870-76 (Box 13, Folder 15)
        - Incoming, 25 Sep 1860-92 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - GENERATION III
    - Ames, Adelbert (1835-1933)
      - Biographical materials
        [see also Ames, Blanche Ames]
        - Correspondence, articles, and essays, circa 1910-80, 2007, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
        - Obituaries and eulogies, 1933-34 (Box 14, Folder 2)
        - Exam results, marriage certificate, poem and clipping about marriage, pension certification, and calling card template, 1867-1917, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
        - Interview: typescript, 1876 (Box 14, Folder 4)
        - Inventories, affidavits, correspondence and memoranda, and death certificate, 1933-37, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
        - Account books and ledgers, 1933-37 (unfoldered) (Box 14)
        - Diaries, 1866-67 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
        - Excerpts from diaries, 1866-67 (bound typescript, unfoldered) (Box 15)
        - Scrapbook of images of European art, 1866-67 (Box 15, Folder 3)
        - Unidentified diary (photocopy of excerpts), undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
        - Card file: notes on military career of Adelbert Ames, undated (Box 16)
        - Appointment books, 1916-25 (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - Account books, 1893-96 (Box 17, Folder 2)
        - Honors and awards, 1869-1963 (Box 17, Folder 3)
        - Military societies
          - Military Order of the Loyal Legion of the U.S.:programs and receipts, 1868 (Box 17, Folder 4)
          - Society of the Army of Santiago de Cuba: by-laws, correspondence, memoranda, and certificate, 1900-1917, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
        - Report to House of Representatives and Congressional directory, 1869-72 (Box 17, Folder 6)
        - Invitations, 1869-1916 (Box 17, Folder 7)
        - Articles and clippings, 1835-1933 (Box 17, Folder 8)
        - Publications: The Testimony in the Impeachment of Adelbert Ames as Governor of Mississippi, 1977 (2 copies) (Box 17, Folder 9)
        - "Plea for Truth": typescript, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 10)
        - Correspondence about Adelbert Ames, 1957-65 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence
        - Personal
          - Outgoing
            - Ames, Adelbert, Jr. (son), 1914 (Box 18, Folder 1)
            - Ames, Blanche Ames (daughter), 1893-1928 (Box 18, Folder 2-3)
            - Ames, Blanche Butler (wife)
              - Apr 1870-Dec 1871 (Box 18, Folder 4-10)
              - Jan 1872-Nov 1875 (Box 19, Folder 1-13)
              - Apr 1876-Dec 1894 (Box 20, Folder 1-14)
              - 1895-1916 (Box 21, Folder 1-4)
            - Ames, Butler (son), 1892-1933 (Box 21, Folder 5)
            - Ames, Jesse and Martha (parents), 1861-1900, undated (Box 21, Folder 6-7)
            - Ames, John J. (brother), 1861-78 (Box 21, Folder 8)
            - Ames, Oakes (son-in-law), 1919 (Box 21, Folder 9)
            - Borden, Sarah Ames (daughter), 1886-1900 (Box 21, Folder 10)
            - Butler, Benjamin F. (father-in-law), 1870-86 (Box 21, Folder 11)
            - Marshall, Jessie Ames (daughter), 1914-16 (Box 21, Folder 12)
            - Rockefeller, John D. and Roosevelt, Franklin D., undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
            - Stevens, Brooks (son-in-law), 1911 (Box 21, Folder 14)
            - Stevens, Edith Ames (daughter), 1893-1916 (Box 21, Folder 15)
            - Ames children, 1886-96 (Box 21, Folder 16)
          - Incoming
            - Ames, Jesse and Martha (parents), 1870-94 (Box 21, Folder 17)
            - Ames, John T. (brother), 1886, 1903 (Box 21, Folder 18)
            - Other relatives, 1861-99 (Box 21, Folder 19)
        - Professional (includes related documents)
          - Antebellum: 1856, 1860 (Box 22, Folder 1)
          - Civil War: 25 Apr 1861-9 Feb 1865 (Box 22, Folder 2-3)
          - Reconstruction
            - 26 Apr 1865-31 Mar 1870 (Box 22, Folder 4-11)
            - 1 Apr-30 Jun 1870 (Box 23, Folder 1-8)
            - 1 Jul 1870-28 Feb 1871 (Box 24, Folder 1-9)
            - 1 Mar-9 Oct 1871 (Box 25, Folder 1-9)
            - 1 Nov 1871-15 Mar 1872 (Box 26, Folder 1-9)
            - 16 Mar-29 Jun 1872 (Box 27, Folder 1-7)
            - 1 Jul 1872-7 Feb 1873 (Box 28, Folder 1-9)
            - 8 Feb-30 Apr 1873 (Box 29, Folder 1-6)
            - 1 May 1873-2 Feb 1897, undated (Box 30, Folder 1-9)
            - Burrigan, Joseph: re: superintendence of National Cemeteries, Jan-Mar, 1873 (Box 30, Folder 10)
            - Knight, Captain Newton, 1871-73 (Box 30, Folder 11)
            - White, D.W.: re: appointment as Chancery Clerk of Tallahatchie County, Mississippi, 1870-73 (Box 30, Folder 12)
            - Mississippi judgeships, 1872-73 (Box 30, Folder 13)
            - Tobacco statistics, 1872 (Box 30, Folder 14)
          - Spanish American War
            - Medical supplies: correspondence and reports, Jan-Dec, 1898 (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
            - Military orders, 1898 (Box 31, Folder 3)
            - Speeches, 1912, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 4)
          - Friends and associates
            - Garner, James W., 1899-1900 (Box 31, Folder 5)
            - Hoover, Herbert, 1932 (Box 31, Folder 6)
            - Lynch, John R., 1914 (Box 31, Folder 7)
            - Riley, Franklin, 1900-01 (Box 31, Folder 8)
            - Spear, Ellis, 1910-13 (Box 31, Folder 9)
            - Taft, William Howard, 1912 (Box 31, Folder 10)
            - Wilson, James H., 1912-14 (Box 31, Folder 11)
            - Miscellaneous, 1892-1932, undated (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - Financial materials
        - Ames Mill (Northfield, Minnesota): correspondence, 1902-06 (Box 31, Folder 13)
        - North Star Mine (Silverton, Colorado): correspondence, 1896-1902, undated (Box 31, Folder 14)
        - Miscellaneous bills and receipts, 1891-1905, undated (Box 32, Folder 1-8)
    - Ames, Blanche Butler (1847-1939)
      - Biographical materials
        - Diary, 1870 (Box 33, Folder 1)
        - Poems about Blanche Butler Ames, 1869-70 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Financial and legal materials
        - General correspondence, 1919-38, undated (Box 33, Folder 3-4)
        - Widow's claim to veteran's pension: correspondence, 1933-34 (Box 33, Folder 5)
        - Annual statements (Box 33, Folder 6)
        - Account books and ledgers, 1919-39 (Box 33, Folder 7-8)
        - Powers of attorney and related correspondence, 1918-20, 1931 (Box 33, Folder 9)
        - Estate settlement
          - Wills and related correspondence, 1918-38 (Box 34, Folder 1-2)
          - Correspondence and memoranda, 1939-50, undated (Box 34, Folder 3-5)
          - Appraisals and valuations, 1939-40 (Box 34, Folder 6)
          - Executors' accounting documents, 1940-45, undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
          - Loans, gifts, and other disbursements, 1903-41, undated (Box 34, Folder 8)
          - Checkbook, ledgers, and receipts, 1939-42, undated (Box 34, Folder 9)
          - Ledger and cash flow, 1939-45 (Box 34, Folder 10-11)
          - Ledgers and cancelled checks, 1939-45 (unfoldered) (Box 35)
      - Filet work, undated
        [see Box 137]
        - Correspondence
          - Personal
            - Outgoing
              - Ames, Adelbert (husband)
                - Apr 1870-Jul 1873 (Box 36, Folder 1-8)
                - Aug 1873-Aug 1878 (Box 37, Folder 1-11)
                - Jul 1879-Feb 1909, undated (Box 38, Folder 1-11)
              - Ames, Adelbert, Jr. (son), 1893-1937, undated (Box 38, Folder 12)
              - Ames, Blanche Ames (daughter)
                - 1891-97 (Box 38, Folder 13)
                - 1898-1939, undated (Box 39, Folder 1-4)
              - Ames, Butler (son), 1891-1939 (Box 39, Folder 5-6)
              - Ames, Jesse (father-in-law), 1875 (Box 40, Folder 1)
              - Borden, Sarah Ames (daughter), 1896-1923 (Box 40, Folder 2)
              - Butler, Benjamin F. (father), 1861-83) (Box 40, Folder 3)
              - Butler, Sarah Hildreth (mother), 1860-76 (Box 40, Folder 4-11)
              - Marshall, Jessie Ames (daughter), 1900-31 (Box 40, Folder 12)
              - Stevens, Edith Ames (daughter), 1896-1923 (Box 40, Folder 13)
              - Ames daughters, 1896 (Box 40, Folder 14)
              - Ames children, 1893-1925 (Box 40, Folder 15)
              - Others (non-family), 1862 (Box 40, Folder 16)
            - Incoming
              - Parton, James, 1870 (Box 40, Folder 17)
              - Spofford, Harriet, 1876 (Box 40, Folder 18)
              - Others, 1861-1939 (Box 40, Folder 19)
        - Writings
          - Character notes for the fictional "Jabez Stout," 1902 (Box 41, Folder 1)
          - Book: Chronicles From the Nineteenth Century: Family Letters of Blanche Butler and Adelbert Ames 1957
            - Typescripts, carbon copies, and photocopies
              - Section I: (pp. 871-1095), Jan-Dec 1872 (Box 41, Folder 2)
              - Section II: (pp. 1-762), Jan 1873-Dec 1874 (Box 41, Folder 3-8)
              - Section II: (pp. 763-1895), Jan 1875-Aug 1893 (Box 42, Folder 1-9)
              - Section II: (pp. 1896-2119), Feb 1894-Nov 1898 (Box 43, Folder 1-2)
              - Poems about:
                - Blanche Butler Ames, 1869 (Box 43, Folder 3)
                - Benjamin F. Butler, undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
                - Sarah Hildreth Butler, undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
              - Ames, Adelbert
                - Military record, undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
                - Executive documents, 1869-70 (Box 43, Folder 7)
                - Spanish American War documents and photographs, circa 1898 (Box 43, Folder 8)
                - Trial testimony: John T. Ames and John Handy vs. Adelbert Ames and Benjamin F. Butler, undated (Box 43, Folder 9)
              - Correspondence
                - Ames, Adelbert with parents and brother, 1861-75 (Box 43, Folder 10)
                - Ames, Blanche Butler and Sarah Hildreth Butler, 1860-76 (Box 43, Folder 11-13)
                - Condolence letters to Blanche Butler Ames re: death of Sarah Hildreth Butler, 1878 (Box 43, Folder 14)
                - Butler, Benjamin F. to Blanche Butler Ames, 1888-1891 (Box 43, Folder 15)
                - Ames, Adelbert and Blanche Butler Ames
                - Apr-Dec 1870 (Box 43, Folder 16)
                - Jan 1871-Nov 1873 (Box 44, Folder 1-6)
                - Jul 1874-Oct 1879 (Box 45, Folder 1-14)
                - May 1880-Oct 1903 (Box 46, Folder 1-7)
                - Excerpts of letters
                - Jan 1874-Dec 1875 (Box 46, Folder 8-9)
                - Jan-May 1876 (Box 47, Folder 1-2)
                - Copy of excerpts, Jan 1874-May 1876 (Box 47, Folder 3-4)
                - "Letters probably not needed," Mar 1877-Oct 1903 (Box 47, Folder 5-11)
                - "Letters omitted"
                - 1860-76 (Box 48, Folder 1-6)
                - 1877-98 (Box 49, Folder 1-3)
              - "Duplicates," 1870-77, undated (Box 49, Folder 4-10)
            - Galley proofs, circa 1957 (Box 49, Folder 11-12)
            - Notes, circa 1957 (Box 49, Folder 13)
            - Correspondence and clippings, 1957-71 (Box 49, Folder 14)
            - Copy of published book (2 volumes) (Box 50)
      - Ames, Oliver III (1831-1895): correspondence, inventory of house contents, and copper nameplate, 1890-92, 1919, undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Ames, Anna Coffin Ray: correspondence with Oakes and Blanche Ames Ames, 1915-17, undated (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Butler, Ben-Israel: biographical information and correspondence, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Butler, Paul
        - Will and clipping, 1918 (Box 51, Folder 4)
        - Financial materials, and related correspondence, 1901-18 (Box 51, Folder 5)
        - Estate
          - Correspondence and related documents, 1918-68, undated (Box 51, Folder 6-16)
          - Correspondence and related documents, undated (Box 52, Folder 1-3)
          - Colorado and New Mexico real estate (includes Butler Ranch): correspondence and reports, 1919-37, undated (Box 52, Folder 4-5)
        - Correspondence, 1876-78 (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Butler, Joanna (aka Anna): correspondence, 1922-1940s (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - GENERATION IV
      - Ames, Adelbert, Jr. 1880-1955
        - Biographical materials
          - Obituaries, honors and awards, articles, clippings, essay, and life chronology, 1923-55, undated (Box 52, Folder 8)
          - Articles by Roy Behrens and related correspondence, 1987-98 (Box 52, Folder 9)
        - Correspondence
          - Ames, Adelbert and Blanche Butler Ames (parents), 1918-39, undated (Box 52, Folder 10)
          - Ames, Blanche Ames (sister), 1915-55, undated (Box 52, Folder 11)
          - Ames, Butler (brother), 1891 (Box 52, Folder 12)
          - Marshall, Jessie Ames (sister), 1929-33 (Box 52, Folder 13)
          - Miscellaneous, 1911, 1935 (Box 52, Folder 14)
        - Writings: bulletins and typescripts, 1921-25, undated (Box 52, Folder 15)
      - Ames, Fanny Vose Hazen: correspondence, undated (Box 52, Folder 16)
      - Ames, Blanche Ames (1879-1969)
        - Biographical materials
          - Birth and marriage certificates, obituaries and eulogies, "Who's Who in America" forms, articles, essays, and clippings, 1899-1992, undated (Box 53, Folder 1)
          - Guidelines for unidentified health regimen, 1909 (Box 53, Folder 2)
          - Passport, circa 1920 (Box 53, Folder 3)
          - Passenger list for ship "Santa Clara" and Florida itinerary, 1940, 1960 (Box 53, Folder 4)
          - Membership cards and certificates, 1942-65, undated (Box 53, Folder 5)
          - Award, 1958 (Box 53, Folder 6)
          - 80th birthday celebration, Feb 1958
            - Correspondence, poems, and telegrams (Box 53, Folder 7)
            - Responses to toasts, by BAA (Box 53, Folder 8)
          - Address and Christmas lists, 1962-63, undated (Box 53, Folder 9)
          - Illness charts, 1965-66 (Box 53, Folder 10)
          - Burial: correspondence, 1969 (Box 53, Folder 11)
          - Diaries (incomplete)
            - 1893-1903 (Box 53, Folder 12-16)
            - 1905-54 (Box 54, Folder 1-4)
          - Malus "Blanche Ames," 1991 (Box 54, Folder 4a)
          - Smith College
            - Scrapbook, and loose items found in scrapbook, circa 1896-1900
              [see also Box 138]
              - Photographs
                - Classmates (Box 55, Folder 1)
                - Groups (Box 55, Folder 2)
                - Dramatics (Box 55, Folder 3)
                - Basketball team (Box 55, Folder 4)
                - Various people and buildings (Box 55, Folder 5)
            - Poems, cards, invitations, and memorabilia, circa 1895-99 (Box 55, Folder 6)
            - Letter from Adelbert Ames, 1898 (Box 55, Folder 7)
            - Class schedule, undated (Box 55, Folder 8)
            - Award for artwork, 1899 (Box 55, Folder 9)
            - Drawings, undated (Box 55, Folder 10)
            - Drafts of skits, undated (Box 55, Folder 11)
            - Smith College programs and songbook, undated (Box 55, Folder 12)
            - Clippings, 1898-99 (Box 55, Folder 13)
            - Class of 1899
              - Constitution (Box 55, Folder 14)
              - Commencement
                - Programs and lists of names (Box 55, Folder 15)
                - Ivy Day: program and notes (Box 55, Folder 16)
              - Reunion programs and alumnae registers, 1901-44 (Box 55, Folder 17)
              - Alumnae correspondence, 1899-1966, undated (Box 55, Folder 18)
              - Oakes Ames Botanical Library Fund: correspondence, 1957 (Box 55, Folder 19)
              - Miscellaneous, 1896-99, undated (Box 55, Folder 20)
            - Dramatics
              - "Rouge et Verte" or "Five Long Years," 1898
                - Draft (Box 56, Folder 1)
                - Floor plan (enclosed in draft) (Box 56, Folder 2)
              - The Winter's Tale by Shakespeare (Box 56)
                - Notebook with enclosed script, 1899 (Box 56, Folder 3)
                - Program and documents enclosed in notebook, 1899 (Box 56, Folder 4)
                - Photographs, 1899 (Box 56, Folder 5)
          - Memorabilia, 1930, undated (Box 56, Folder 6)
        - Financial and legal materials
          [See also SERIES III: INDIVIDUALS - Generation III - Butler, Paul]
          - Codicil, will, and related documents, 1933-74 (Box 56, Folder 7)
          - Estate of William H. Ames: correspondence and court documents, 1921-33 (Box 56, Folder 8)
            [see also SERIES III: INDIVIDUALS - Generation IV - Ames, William Hadwen]
          - Unidentified legal issue involving C. Brooks Stevens: correspondence, 1919-20 (Box 56, Folder 9)
          - Insurance coverage: correspondence and essay, 1923-66 (Box 56, Folder 10)
          - Charitable donations and membership dues, 1925-68, n.d (Box 56, Folder 11)
          - Correspondence and memoranda pertaining to investment accounts, dividends, and taxes
            - 1900-41 (Box 57, Folder 1-10)
            - 1942-69, undated (Box 58, Folder 1-6)
          - Banking and investment management reports (mostly Kidder, Peabody, and Co.), 1946-63 (Box 58, Folder 7)
          - Account books: 1905-14, 1920-22 (Box 58, Folder 8-9)
          - Annual statements
            - 1926-35 (Box 58, Folder 10)
            - 1940-47 (Box 59, Folder 1)
          - Bills and receipts, 1916-63, undated (Box 59, Folder 2-6)
          - Bank statements and cancelled checks, 1899-1967, undated (Box 59, Folder 7-11)
          - Management of family assets
            - "Union of Workers and Minors": correspondence, 1942-43 (Box 60, Folder 1)
            - General correspondence and memoranda, 1924, 1943-57, undated (Box 60, Folder 2-4)
            - American Bolt Co., 1918-21 (Box 60, Folder 4A)